titicrafty.com 2019-07-18

# Privacy Policy | The Crafting Nook

This Privacy Policy explains how information about you is collected, used and disclosed by TCN. This Privacy Policy applies to information we collect when you use “Services”, or when you otherwise interact with us.

We may change this Privacy Policy from time to time. If we make changes, we will notify you by revising the “Last Updated” date at the top of this policy and, in some cases, we may provide you with additional notice (such as by adding a statement to our website or by sending you a notification). We encourage you to review our Privacy Policy whenever you access the Services or otherwise interact with us to stay informed about our information practices and the ways you can help protect your privacy.

The Crafting Nook may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page from time to time to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from 10 May 2018.

This blog is a personal blog written and edited by me. For questions about this blog, please contact  [cami@thecraftingnook.com](mailto:cami@thecraftingnook.com).

This blog accepts forms of cash advertising, sponsorship, **affiliate programs** , paid insertions or other forms of compensation.  You will not be charged anything extra if you click one of these links, but I will receive a small commission from the affiliate company if you do choose to buy something.

We are a professional review site that receives compensation from the companies whose products we review. We test each product thoroughly and give high marks to only the very best. We are independently owned and the opinions expressed here are our own.

This blog abides by word of mouth marketing standards. We believe in honesty of relationship, opinion, and identity. The compensation received may influence the advertising content, topics or posts made in this blog. That content, advertising space or post will be clearly identified as paid or sponsored content.

The owner(s) of this blog is compensated to provide opinion on products, services, websites and various other topics. Even though the owner(s) of this blog receives compensation for our posts or advertisements, we always give our honest opinions, findings, beliefs, or experiences on those topics or products. The views and opinions expressed on this blog are purely the bloggers’ own. Any product claim, statistic, quote or other representation about a product or service should be verified with the manufacturer, provider or party in question.

This blog does not contain any content which might present a conflict of interest.

To get your own policy, go to [http://www.disclosurepolicy.org](http://www.disclosurepolicy.org/)

### Collection of Information

 **Information You Provide to Us.** We collect information you provide directly to us. For example, we collect information when you create an account, participate in any interactive features of the Services, subscribe to a newsletter or email list, participate in an event, survey, contest or promotion, make a purchase, communicate with us via third-party social media sites, request customer support or otherwise communicate with us.

The types of information we may collect include your name, email address, password, postal address, phone number, gender, date of birth, occupation, employer information, photo, payment information (such as your credit or debit card and billing address), preference or interest data, and any other information you choose to provide.

If you provide an email address to invite a friend to participate in the Services, we will collect that email address and use it to send your friend such an invitation.

### Information We Collect Automatically

When you access or use our Services, we may automatically collect information about you, including:

 **Log Information:** We collect log information about your use of the Services, including your Internet Protocol (“IP”) address, web request, access times, pages viewed, web browser, links clicked and the page you visited before navigating to the Services.

 **Mobile Device Information:** We collect information about the mobile device you use to access our Services, including the hardware model, operating system, and version, unique device identifiers, mobile network information and information about your use of our mobile applications.

 **Information Collected by Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies:** We and our service providers use various technologies to collect information, including cookies and web beacons. Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory that help us improve our Services and your experience, see which areas and features of our Services are popular, and count visits. Web beacons are electronic images that may be used in our Services or emails and help deliver cookies, count visits, and understand usage and campaign effectiveness. For more information about cookies, and how to disable them, please see “Your Choices” below.

### Information We Collect From Other Sources

We may also obtain information from other sources and combine that with information we collect through our Services. For example, if you create or log into your account through a third-party social media site, we will have access to certain information from that site, such as your name, account information and friends lists, in accordance with the authorization procedures determined by such social media site; we may also collect information about you when you post content to our pages/feeds on third-party social media sites.

 **Use of Information**

We may use information about you for various purposes, including to:

  * Provide, maintain, improve and promote our products and services;
  * Provide and deliver the information, products and services you request, process transactions and send you related information, including confirmations and receipts;
  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts, and support and administrative messages;
  * Respond to your comments, questions and requests, and provide customer service;
  * Communicate with you about products, services, surveys, offers, promotions, rewards and events offered by Company and others, and provide news and information we think will be of interest to you;
  * Monitor and analyze trends, usage and activities in connection with our Services;
  * Personalize and improve the Services and provide advertisements, content or features that match user profiles or interests;
  * Facilitate contests, sweepstakes and promotions, and process and deliver entries and rewards;
  * Link or combine with information we get from others to help understand your needs and provide you with better service; and
  * Carry out any other purpose for which the information was collected.

The information we collect is governed by U.S. law. By accessing or using the Services or otherwise providing information to us, you consent to the processing and transfer of information in and to the U.S. and other countries.

 **Sharing of Information**

We may share information about you as follows or as otherwise described in this Privacy Policy:

  * With vendors, consultants and other service providers who need access to such information to carry out work or perform services on our behalf;
  * When you participate in the interactive areas of our Services, certain information you provide may be displayed to other users, such as your name, photo, comments and other information you choose to provide;
  * In response to a request for information if we believe disclosure is in accordance with, or required by, any applicable law, regulation or legal process;
  * If we believe your actions are inconsistent with our user agreements or policies, or to protect the rights, property and safety of Company or others;
  * In connection with, or during negotiations of, any merger, sale of company assets, financing or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company; and
  * With your consent or at your direction. Social Sharing Features

The Services may offer social sharing features and other integrated tools (such as the Facebook “Like” button), which let you share actions you take on our Services with other media, and vice versa. Your use of such features enables the sharing of information with your friends or the public, depending on the settings you establish with the entity that provides the social sharing feature. For more information about the purpose and scope of data collection and processing in connection with social sharing features, please visit the privacy policies of the entities that provide these features.

### Advertising and Analytics Services Provided by Others

We may allow others to serve advertisements on our behalf across the Internet and to provide analytics services. These entities may use cookies, web beacons and other technologies to collect information about your use of the Services and other websites, including your IP address, web browser, pages viewed, time spent on pages, links clicked and conversion information. This information may be used by Company and others to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests on our Services and other websites and better understand your online activity. For more information about interest-based ads, or to opt out of having your web browsing information used for behavioral advertising purposes by companies that participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance, please visit www.aboutads.info/choices.

### Security

Company takes reasonable measures to help protect information about you from loss, theft, misuse and unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration and destruction.

### Your Choices

 **Account Information**

You may review, correct or modify information maintained in your online account at any time by logging into your account and updating your profile information or by emailing us at cami@thecraftingnook.com. If you wish to delete or deactivate your account, please email us at cami@thecraftingnook.com, but note that some information you provide through the Services may continue to be accessible (e.g., comments you submit through the Services) and that we may continue to store information about you as required by law or for legitimate business purposes. We may also retain cached or archived copies of information about you for a certain period of time.

 **Cookies**

Most web browsers are set to accept cookies by default. If you prefer, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies. Please note that if you choose to remove or reject cookies, this could affect the availability or functionality of our Services

### How we use cookies

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyse web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyse data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

 **Cookie Opt Out**

You can opt out of cookies using the Network Advertising Initiative opt-out page at this page;  
<http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>

Finally as mentioned above, you can choose to disable or selectively turn off cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings.

 **Promotional Communications**

You may opt out of receiving promotional communications from us by following the instructions in those communications or by sending an email to cami@thecraftingnook.com. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional communications, such as those about your account or our ongoing business relations.

 **Advertising**

Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies as well. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers. We may use advertising service vendors to help present advertisements on the website, one of which is [https://www.adthrive.com/. ](https://www.adthrive.com/)These vendors may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and Service Provider disclaims all liability in connection therewith.

 **Push Notifications/Alerts**

With your consent, we may send push notifications or alerts to your mobile device. You can deactivate these messages at any time by changing the notification settings on your mobile device.

 **Links to other websites**

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

 **ALSO… IMAGE POLICY**

I love it when you love my work! You may use any of my photos or recipes from a post you enjoy here to be featured on your site, as long as you provide a link back to me and notify me either in the comments or with a direct email. If you feature a photo, it may not be accompanied by the project tutorial, whether in my own words as it originally appears or paraphrased. I do not permit photos of my family to be shared without my express written consent for each photo used.  
I know that by publishing on the internet, anyone can see what I share, but it’s still my intellectual property and it only belongs here at TitiCrafty unless you get prior written permission from me for each post.

Thanks for playing fair and respecting my copyright!

'Til Next time!

My name is Camila Rojas but everyone call me Cami. I'm a mommy, blogger, baker, do it yourselfer, crafter and graphic designer. Owner and founder of The Crafting Nook {formerly TitiCrafty} and TCN Design Studio: web design for bloggers. Join me on my crazy adventures!

This website uses cookies to improve your experience. We'll assume you're ok with this, but you can opt-out if you wish.I Accept I Reject [Read More...](https://thecraftingnook.com/cookie-policy/)
